# **Frances Vevers**

francesvevers@gmail.com +447837760350 Huddersfield, Kirklees Full driving license

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative, logical and detail oriented developer with over ten years experience working across public and private sectors. I have excellent interpersonal communication skills and I can manage my time efficiently, with a proven track-record of providing excellent customer service and support to clients and colleagues.

### **WORK HISTORY**

# Front End Developer

May 2022 - June 2023

Permanent | Marigold | Remote

- Developing and supporting SaaS product Vuture
- Building responsive email templates and landing pages using HTML, CSS and Javascript
- Providing client training via Zoom
- Testing using Litmus
- Creating technical and support documentation
- Responsible for project managing build and testing process
- Advising on email and web best practices and accessibility during scoping/design process
- Managing tickets using Jira, Zendesk and Slack

### Web Developer

January 2022 - May 2022

Permanent Nouveau Beauty Group Remote

- Developing and theming Wordpress websites and plugins using PHP, HTML, CSS and Javascript
- Providing backend maintenance on Wordpress websites and Magento stores.
- Using Git version control for cross team development and updates
- A/B testing using Google Optimise
- Working closely with the Marketing team to monitor and improve SEO
- Proof-read and posted blog posts and case studies
- Working with UX designer to improve user journey and conversion
- Using Agile methodologies, managing tickets and workload with Trello
- Completed and debugged online booking system

Systems Developer

January 2016 - January 2022

Permanent Kirklees College Huddersfield

 Ongoing maintenance and development of college systems including Wordpress website, Moodle VLE and Sharepoint

- Providing support via service desk ticket management
- Using SQL and Microsoft Server Management Studio to troubleshoot college systems
- Reporting on targets and KPIs of the IT team
- Acting as liaison with outside agencies
- Leading development meetings with various stakeholders on internal development of college systems and support
- Completed project on IT customer support leading to new ticket management system being rolled out
- Over saw completion and launch of new college Wordpress website
- Developing processes and training staff on 3rd party Wordpress plugins (ACF, Elementor and Custom Post Types) to create content
- Project managed development of bespoke online applications system using ASP.net and Advanced Pro suite
- Monitoring Google Analytics to improve SEO
- Sitting on Diversity and Inclusivity working group to advise on W3C web standards and accessibility
- Working with cross college teams (eg Marketing, Graphics and Student Support) to improve user experience and meet their targets

# **VLE and Digital Development Officer**

May 2014 - January 2016

Permanent | Leeds College of Music | Leeds

- Lead developer on project to build a student intranet and forum
- Managing Moodle maintenance including theme design, updates and backups
- Creating support documentation for staff and students
- Providing 1st and 2nd line support for students and staff on Windows and Mac systems
- Supporting students with building their own Wordpress portfolio sites

# **Development Co-ordinator**

July 2010 - January 2016

Permanent | NDNA | Huddersfield, Kirklees

- Lead developer on online training site using Moodle
- Developed sales process for online courses
- Creating online learning content, e-modules and SCORM packages
- Redesigned publications range using Adobe InDesign and Microsoft Word for content including streamlining their update and proofing process
- Developed new sales reporting process for publications

- Provided customer support for external clients
- Involved in various projects on technical systems development and writing bids
- Improved SEO strategies and monitored website analytics

# **EDUCATION**

# **BSc Degree**

University of Portsmouth - 2009

Digital Media 2.1

Modules included: Software Development Processes, Java, Javascript, Photoshop, Motion Capture, 3D animation and Game Design.

## A-Level, AS Level

Greenhead College - 2005
English, Art, Theatre Studies, Psychology | A-D

#### **GCSE**

Honley High School - 2003

English, Maths, Science, IT, French, Art, Graphics, Media Studies, RE | A\* - D

# **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Jira, Slack, Adobe Photoshop, Service desk, Agile, Business Analysis, CRM, Data Analytics, Microsoft Office, Project Management, Change Management

### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Musical Theatre, Pro Wrestling, Drawing, Coffee

### REFERENCES

References available on request